#### Kathleen Baker

Address: Mullagh, Cavan / Clonsilla Dublin 15 Email: kathleenbaker9@gmail.com Phone: 0837 3246214

# **Professional Summary**

Quality driven Health and Safety Professional working in the food production industry. Highly organised, strong communication and documentation skills. Up to date knowledge in health and safety practices, legislation and EU directives. Team player and liaise with all members of the workforce to ensure occupational and environmental health and safety practices are promoted. Extensive experience in incident and accident reporting systems, audits and monitoring of corrective actions until close out. Dedicated to continuous professional development.

## **Work History**

Health and Safety Intern (Oct 2018 – July 2019) Health and Safety Graduate (Jul 2019 – July 2012), H&S Manager (Jul 2021- Present), Kepak Clonee.

- Liaise with site personnel regarding site accident, incident and near misses.
- Reporting and recording investigations, ensuring corrective and preventative actions are formulated and implemented.
- Assist in the preparation for legal cases in relation to workplace accidents and injuries.
- Identify and manage H&S training needs and executing same.
- Liaise with site personnel in carrying out sufficient risk assessments for all activities.
- Carry out site safety observation audits, identify areas for improvement, document corrective actions and support BU managers to implement recommendations made.
- Analyse site data to determine improvement recommendations for potential areas of increased risk.
- Prepare presentations and reports for site meetings with the BU managers and assist in developing H&S strategic plans as required for site.
- Enforce the effective implementation of H&S practices, processes, standards and systems.
- Support higher management to meet H&S performance objectives with the aim of improving site safety and commercial objectives.
- Coordinate H&S documentation and ensure any changes/updates are captured and implemented.
- Manage the co-ordination site inductions and toolbox talks.
- Management of employees. Approval of holidays, development reviews.
- Manual handling training for employees undergoing induction and refresher manual handling training for existing employees.

Farrells Public House, Mullagh, Co. Cavan (Jan 2019 – Jul 2019)

- Consisted of stock keeping and product ordering.
- Cleaning and ensuring all product are fully stocked on shelves.
- Waiting on customers.

Tyrrells Public House, Mullagh, Co. Cavan (July 2017 – Jan 2019)

- Consisted of stock keeping and product ordering.
- Cleaning and ensuring all product are fully stocked on shelves.
- Waiting on customers.

Swimming Instructor, Kells Swimming Pool, Kells, Co. Meath (Sep 2015 – July 2018) (Part Time)

- Teaching the basic swimming strokes to children from the ages of 5-10 years old.
- Volunteer for special needs swimming lessons on Saturday mornings.

## Education

Eureka Secondary School, Kells, Co. Meath (2012 – 2017)

Completed my junior and leaving cert in Eureka Secondary School.

Dunboyne College Of Further Education, Dunboyne, Co. Meath (2017 – 2018)

• Completed a pre-university business course. I was then offered a position in Maynooth University to study international business, which I declined to work and study at the same time.

#### Level 6 In Occupational Safety And Health, Atu Sligo (2019 – 2021)

- Modules Studied: Introductory science, Foundations in occupational safety and health, communications, Introductory science 2, Health and safety representation, sector specific workplace hazards, Foundations of hazard identification and risk assessment, physical and chemical safety, construction safety, occupational safety and health legislation, electrical machinery and fire safety and safety practitioner skills.
- I received top of my class award while studying the level 6.

# Level 7 In Occupational Safety And Health, Atu Sligo (2021 – Present (Finished in May))

- Modules Studied: Safety legislation 1, Hazard and risk control, Management of hazardous materials and processes, OSH Business case communication, Occupational hygiene physical agents, human and Organisational safety factors, Occupational health & biohazards, Environmental topics in the workplace, Safety Legislation 2, Construction safety and contractor management, Occupational hygiene chemical agents and workplace health promotion and wellness.
- I will be moving on in September of 2023 to study BSc (Hons) in Occupational Safety and Health Management (Online). I am extremely capable of studying and working simultaneously.

#### Other relevant trainings completed:

- IBEC Diploma in Professional Competence- 2021, Distinction
- QQI Level 6 Manual Handling Instructor- 2021, Distinction
- First Aider- 2020
- Fire Warden 2021
- Racking Inspection Course- 2021
- LOTO awareness- 2021
- Certificate in Handling Refrigerants (Ammonia) 2022
- Legionella Awareness Training- 2022

#### Skills

IT – Excel, word, PowerPoint, Office, Outlook Reporting Planning & organising Good team player Excellent time management Leadership Manual handling Instructor

# Personal Attributes

Self-motivated
Organised,
Excellent work ethic,
People orientated
Problem Solver
Skilled multi-tasker